August
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
Saionji-sensei...
Please get a little sleep.
I'm fine.
In fact, if I fall asleep now, I won't get this done.
Hey.
Let's get a breath of fresh air.
We're taking a break.
Okay.
See you later.
You guys take a break too when you get a chance.
Call my cell if you need anything.
By now, we should barely make it tonight.
Let's go.
Daikichi!
It's hot...
It feels like ice.
You're too cold.
Well, if I turn off the AC, the boys mess up the manuscript with their sweat.
The body can cool down from stress, too...
Oh yeah?
About that new offer you were talking about the other day...
I don't think letting the quality of your current work drop
is worth taking it on...
But Ma-chan, you don't really have a strong constitution or will.
And you're making a decent living as it is,
so there's no need to be greedy.
But...
What?
Right now, the spotlight's on me,
but who knows what'll happen next year.
Any number of younger rookie artists will gradually appear...
They could turn their backs on me, just like that.
Ma-chan, you worry too much about what could go wrong.
It's unhealthy.
You have an ink mark on your face again.
Oh yeah?
Tch...
Ma-chan, you're a girl, so...
I'm not a girl!
I'm a mangaka!
I'm going home to work!
I'm sorry for making a scene...
Jeez...
Going to work is a pain...
Good morning.
I called you before.
Sorry. It was just so hot...
Are you cooling off by doing that?
Yeah.
Want to make your lunch?
Yeah!
Hey, you!
Give me a hand here!
Okay!
Rin's summer vacation has begun.
In the morning, we make her lunch together,
and then Rin goes to a day care center.
How about we visit Grandpa's grave next Saturday?
It's almost O-Bon,
Note: O-Bon = Holiday in which people honor their ancestors
and since it's your...
What? You don't want to go?
After all, the bellflowers haven't bloomed yet...
It looks like it'll take a little more time.
Well, this time, we'll buy flowers at a florist,
and we can go again when your flowers bloom.
I guess...
You'd make Grandpa happy by bringing him the bellflowers that you grew.
See? That's what I thought!
But what would make Grandpa happiest is for you to visit.
That's number one.
Yeah.
Okay.
If Rin weren't here, I probably wouldn't be thinking of Grandpa like this.
Rin-chan! Rin-chan!
Kouki-kun!
If you move, it screws the whole thing up!
Oops!
Apricot
Why is your hair so fine to begin with?
I don't know!
What?
Wait a second!
Hey! We're going to be late!
What's with him?
Daikichi, how many more days?
Obon Festival
About ten, I guess...
I found one!
A cicada shell!
A shell?
Huh. This brings back memories...
I've got a bunch of 'em in here.
Gross!
Don't shake them!
We're going to be late!
Hey!
Watch out for cars!
I've been here a lot of times before.
With Grandpa?
Yeah.
I see. Grandma's laid to rest here too, come to think of it.
Grandpa's grandma?
No, my grandma.
Um, Grandpa and Grandma's child is my mom.
And I'm her son.
Your mother is Grandpa's daughter!
But...
Then that makes me your mother's sister...
Crap! I don't want her to go in this direction...
Over here!
Here it is!
Kaga Family Grave
The grave's wet.
That jar...
Masako-san had it...
Ma...
What the heck? She didn't even come to his funeral!
Rin, I'll be right back!
Stay here for a bit!
Pull up the weeds for me!
Okay!
What should I do?
I mean, she goes with a man to visit the grave?
Bark! Bark!
What?! What are you doing here?
I thought you were some crazy person...
I'm supposed to be visiting a grave.
Accent on the "supposed to be."
But I thought maybe I should let you know...
Rin's here, too.
At Grandpa's grave...
Um, I...
Um, Rin's dear to me, so to be honest, I don't often think about you.
I don't care about your circumstances either.
Unless Rin wishes for it, I have no intention of ever having you two meet.
I know that.
But you went out of your way to follow me. What did you want to say?
Do you want to at least get a look at Rin secretly?
Now, we're going to clean the grave off, light incense, and go home like normal.
I think it'll take some time.
Well, Rin is waiting for me.
So do what you want.
We're just going to go about our business.
Rin... Sorry...
Was I gone long?
Um...
Are you okay?
Um... I had to do something...
Never mind, sorry.
Did you wait long?
Not too long.
Were you lonely?
You're weird!
Why are you so nervous?
I'm not weird.
Here.
Right.
Hold it out there.
Okay.
She's no longer a baby...
Blood ties are an amazing thing.
Yep. She looks just like you, Ma-chan.
From behind...
She's pretty cute.
From this distance...
he closely resembles Souichi-san.
Good.
That was a surprise.
Maybe a coincidence like this happened because it's nearly O-Bon.
She's seven years old today.
I see...
I was surprised about your daughter, of course,
but I thought maybe he was your ex-boyfriend...
Give me a break.
I don't think that man's got a bit of intelligence.
Although I can't say what he'd be like given another half a century...
Half... a century?
I suppose that man was her boyfriend...
Hey, Daikichi?
And it's a stretch for me to say it's bad...
Daikichi!
But some people...
Well, she sure found herself a sweetheart fast enough...
Daikichi, I said!
Yes?
Can we go to Grandpa's house?
It's near here, isn't it?
But that's not Grandpa's house anymore.
Is somebody living there?
No. No one's living there now, but the house is my uncle's...
My mom's older brother's house, so...
The family altar is there, too.
I see...
Fine. I'll ask my uncle if we can just go in the yard.
Really?
Only the yard!
Right!
I know the way!
I'm going to try and do that assignment after all.
Seriously?!
Are you sure about this, Ma-chan?
I'm alone for the sake of my work.
I have to do more work.
You're already working plenty!
You work enough for two people!
It's not enough yet...
I have to work so hard that I forget what I had for dinner last night.
Oh, come on. I always forget what I had for dinner the previous night...
If I don't...
If I don't forget many things...
I...
We're almost there!
Kaga
It's the same as before, huh?
But you've totally changed.
They're gone!
The bellflowers!
The dirt is gone too!
The bellflowers were precious to Grandpa!
I'm sure he didn't mean to remove them.
Uncle knows Grandpa's favorite flower, at least.
But they wither up when winter comes.
Maybe he didn't know that they sprout when spring comes again.
The rocks, too...
If you don't spread them all over like this,
weeds will soon spring up and become tough to deal with.
I'm glad we moved Rin's fragrant olive tree.
That saved its life.
But thankfully we have Grandpa's bellflowers at our house too, right?
Because of that, they're still alive!
Exactly!
Maybe change isn't all bad.
But that grave will always be Grandpa's grave, right?
Yeah!
Rin!
Happy birthday.
Happy Birthday
Rin-chan
It's a chocolate one!
Saionji-sensei, can you do the final check?
Are you okay?
You really do seem to be in over your head this time...
When you put it into words like that, my hand stops working, so cut it out!
Go ahead.
I'll finish it, for sure.
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Daikichi, the festival stalls are going to close!
No, they won't!
It sounds like Grandpa.
Kouki-kun is here!
What's wrong?
We're supposed to meet up at the shrine, remember?
Mom is taking too long!
You're not wearing a yukata?
I can't jump with that!
Was that awesome or what?
Where's your mom?
She said she'll leave once she puts on her yukata, so we should meet at the shrine.
Let's go!
Before the festival stalls close!
Daikichi, watch out for cars!
I know!
Wait! It's hard to run in geta!
I'll carry you!
Forget it!
You can carry me!
Tongue twisters!
The frogs matched three Pyocopyoco Pyocopyoco with six Pyocopyoco Pyocopyoco.
Good afternoon, Rin here.
A big typhoon is coming, so I went home with Kouki.
I was scared at first, but then I got excited!
A typhoon is a bit mysterious.
The next story is "A Typhoon Has Come!"
The neighbor's persimmon was eaten by a lot of costumers.
Episode 9
A Typhoon Has Come!